[SLIDE 1] Okay. Welcome. In this lightning talk, I’ll be giving a brief overview
of UCLA Library’s Anti-Racist Pedagogy Workshop Series,
which launched with our first workshop on 27 April 2021 (yay!).
[SLIDE 2] The Teaching & Learning Functional Team is part of UCLA Library’s User Engagement matrixed structure.
The team is currently made up of 10 members with rotating leadership and rotating membership.
It currently includes 8 members from User Engagement, a librarian from the Digital Library Program, and a librarian from Library Special Collections.
One of the central points of our charge is to promote professional development and reflective instructional practices for Library staff.
In the past, this has included a series of Remote Teaching Design Jams and Open Mic events that provide opportunities for professional development & skill-sharing.
[SLIDE 3] In the wake of George Floyd’s murder and as a result of Black-led activism demanding systemic change,
we experienced a period of increased institutional support for anti-racist work, in which the Teaching & Learning Functional Team
considered ways that we could support anti-racist practice in library instruction with three primary stipulations:
1) our approach should center and support BIPOC colleagues, students, staff, and faculty,
2) our intervention should be sustained and meaningful rather than a parachute effort like a one-off workshop or reading list, and
3) we would recognize the limits of our own expertise and identify experts to help fill these gaps.
One of the resulting initiatives was this Anti-Racist Pedagogy Workshop Series.
[SLIDE 4] Our goal for the workshop series is to invite qualified facilitators and experts to present on anti-racist pedagogy and practice
in a series available to all library staff to support anti-racist praxis in teaching & learning in alignment with the Library’s broader anti-racism initiative framework.
In order to provide a scaffolded and sustained engagement with anti-racist praxis and to ensure effective professional development and growth,
we had originally planned 6-8 sessions with invited speakers from September 2020 to June 2021.
For reasons, we currently plan to offer 3 sessions (one per month) from April 2021 to June 2021.
Additionally, recognizing income disparities, material conditions, and the time and labor asked of our presenters and facilitators,
it was important for our team to secure funding to provide some compensation.
So, we are able to provide $500 for each of our speakers thanks to our Associate University Librarian.
We hope that this is helpful for our speakers and shows our gratitude for their work.
[SLIDE 5] Our workshop series is really just starting out.
We had our first session in April with Dr. Michelle Caswell from UCLA’s Information Studies department
to kick off the series with an introduction to critical race theory.
The session was well-received with over 75 attendees and much appreciation for the opportunity.
We’re excited for our next session in May with Dr. Esther Ohito from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill School of Education (Go Heels!)
to talk about critical pedagogies and anti-racist teaching.
I’m particularly excited for this mix of experts inside and outside of Library and Information Studies.
And, we’re hopeful that these sessions will provide opportunities for us to discuss anti-racist instruction in our institutional setting
and consider theoretically and practically how we can implement changes in our own library instruction as well as ways to improve our instruction program.
[SLIDE 6] I’m hopeful that we’ll be able to continue the workshop series beyond June,
though we’ll certainly check-in as we go to make sure that the workshops are providing the skill-building opportunities
that our library instructors need and to make sure that the workshops are meeting our programmatic goals.
If anyone has any suggested speakers or wants to be one of our speakers, I’m happy to hear from you all.
So far, we have received some feedback about making the workshops available beyond UCLA Library either synchronously or through recordings.
In order to create space for open discussion and dialogue and to specifically center UCLA Library as our context and in framing our solutions,
we hadn’t planned on opening them up further or on making recordings available.
In the future, we might explore other opportunities to open up avenues for discussion and engagement on anti-racist pedagogy beyond UCLA Library.
[SLIDE 7] If there are any questions or comments, you can email me at my Library email address (mattweirick@library.ucla.edu)
or my personal professional email address (matt@mattweirick.com).
This recording, along with the slides, captions, and transcript, will be available on my website (academic.mattweirick.com)
if anyone would like to access the materials later. Thanks again.